Amalia Sörlien

EDUCATION

Design and Product Development

Linköping University | 2013-2018 M.Sc in Engineering

The education is as much about design as solving problems and project management. I have both technical and design knowledge throughout the whole product development process, from idea to finished product.

Industrial Design Engineering

San Diego State University | 2016

I started my masters degree with one semester at San Diego State University.

COMPETENCES

Visualization

Photoshop

Illustrator

Adobe XD

InVision

Balsamiq

Development

HTML

CSS

Languages

Swedish

English

Soft skills

Ambitious

Fast learner

Team player

Curious

Positive mindset

PROFILE

I see myself as both a designer and a creative engineer. As a designer, I have a profound interest in human-centred design and user experiences. With a background as an engineer I use my analytical thinking to find smart and feasible solutions and enjoy problem-solving.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Component Owner

Volvo Group Trucks Technology | 2020- present

I am working in a team that develop and maintain our digital Development Portal for 3:rd party applications. As a single point of contact towards stakeholders, I am in continuous collaborations with a cross-functional and global network. Since this is a new field for my department, I have been involved in designing the process for an app's life cycle; from onboarding, industrialization to maintenance.

Human Machine Interface Engineer

Volvo Group Trucks Technology | 2018-2020

As part of an agile development team, I coordinated the projects and the flow of information to the developers. I acted as a link between UX-designers and other stakeholders. My deliveries included viewflows to my team and I was responsible for HMI requirements and the text translation process. To solve different challanges, I facilitated workshops.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Ivy League: Introduction to Negotiation

Online course from Yale University | 2020

Culture Champion

Nominated by my manager to work with our company culture and to facilitate workshops with different teams throughout VGTT |2020

Dynamic Web Application

University course for HTML, CSS and JavaScript development | 2019

SAFe Training

Participated in a two-day certified SAFe agile training | 2019

Driver's License B

2012







